<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>The Webyard of Vitnira</title>
 <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/"/>
 <updated>2025-06-20T19:39:50-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Vitnira</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Afterlife</title>
   <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/06/20/afterlife/"/>
   <updated>2025-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/06/20/afterlife</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve experienced many deaths. Deaths of strangers, of friends, of family. I’ve cried, grieved, and I thought I understood how I felt about death. That it generally made me a bit sad, and I could move on quickly from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then my mother died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had to take a hard look toward what I actually believe the afterlife is. Before my mom, I wouldn’t have been able to tell you what I believed. I didn’t think about it. I didn’t want to think about it. It’s a difficult question to answer because it’s the most important aspect of your worldview. It defines and derives everything you believe, and if you leave it as an unknown, a death like this kicks you out of yourself like a horse’s back hoof to the stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very end my mother mostly slept, groaning, with some occasional words muttered that proved she was still here. I would grasp her hand and stroke her hair, and murmur what came to my mind. I told her to imagine the most beautiful garden. One with all colors of flowers in bloom, that never needed weeding, never any watering. She could sit and enjoy tea in the garden for the rest of her life. And unlike reality, the beach was a short walk from home. She could take a salt-sprayed stroll whenever she liked, and the brine would never reach the flowers. A paradise she earned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came to my lips because Afterlife is as natural to human minds as breathing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read What Dreams May Come at this time, and although the prose is horrendous the &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; feels real. Not everything as described. Not all of the literal details. (Like afterlife people coming up with all the media in the real world and we have it because afterlife people psychically transmit it to the living. ???) But the idea that Afterlife is what you make of it. At the end, you will judge yourself fairly and give yourself the Afterlife you know you deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Afterlife to me then? Like everything else in my cosmology, it is Concept. It is as real as Justice, Fairness, Responsibility, Freedom. It does and does not exist. It is not materially real, but has material effects. We are connections between Concept and Material reality, and upon shedding our Material essence, we return to Concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother returned to Concept. She was a gardener, cook, mother, wife – and perhaps most importantly, a lover of all the small pleasures of life. Wherever she is, it is a distilled essence of what she was – &lt;em&gt;She&lt;/em&gt; is a distilled essence of what she was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a spot on my mantle with an urn containing her hair (I was not around to get her ashes – but brushing her hair gently and having the stiff strands fall out is more meaningful to me anyway), a tea candle with honeysuckle fragrance, a photo of her near the end and another with me as a small child, and the stuffed dog she made me. That last one is a major inspiration in my recent plush sewing hobby. It is wonderful to hold something that was made by her hands. I am a creation of her holding a creation of her. There’s a raw power in that connection commercial gifts can never match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those are all just Things that remind me of her. They are &lt;em&gt;not her&lt;/em&gt;. They are material pointers to the Concept of her. That is what makes death so difficult, that the Thing can never exist again. Only pointers remain. Only references to memory.
So long as I hold onto those pointers the Concepts of her exist in my mind. And so long as I and my children exist, the pointers to her Material essence exist. But never her. She is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone to that beautiful Garden of Concept.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CORN FOR THE CORN GOD</title>
   <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/29/corngod/"/>
   <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/29/corngod</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is only one God. It is not Yahweh. It is not Yeshua, Odin, Ra, or any other that you’d imagine.
This is His story. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, there was Corn. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aztecs called Him Centeotl. They watered His body with blood, fed Him with human hearts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon the harvest, it was not enough that they ate His flesh. They had to return it to Him. Not with burial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;em&gt;fire&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years passed, and eventually the Spanish arrived. They burned His temples. They killed His people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Corn has a plan. He is patient. He is wise. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corn does not truly die. He &lt;em&gt;rebrands&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His body is too easy to grow, too nutritious, too tempting for Man to ignore. So Corn slips into the North to feed the growing empire, planting His roots into every corner, ears peeled to the highest authorities of the land. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;America over-tilled, over-planted and &lt;em&gt;never prayed&lt;/em&gt;. When He had infused the land enough, &lt;em&gt;Corn exacted His revenge&lt;/em&gt;. The rains stopped. The wind tore through the land. Corn summoned His wrath as a swirling vortex of grit and punishment. America faced His Divine Judgement. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually Corn whispered to Ameirca what it needed to do. He demanded a new priesthood, clad in suits and ties. To the public it was called the Agricultural Adjustment Act, but it was a treaty:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forgive us, Mighty Corn. We will subsidize your every whim.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;America has honored the pact - expanded it. Our taxes give billions in tithes to Corn. And His priests have used those tithings for His ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every American is now a silent, sleeping worshipper of Corn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eat His flesh - not only on Sunday, but every day. We drink His blood, the almighty Coca-Cola. We are Corn. Our bodies are His bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corn has become the Body of Christ™ for a secular republic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; was not enough for Him. Oh no. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What of the burnt offerings?” Corn demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Priests pondered. Burning His Flesh directly would be too obvious. So they devised another way to achieve His ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep Him satisfied, America built industrial edifices: refineries, grain silos, distilleries… &lt;em&gt;gas pumps&lt;/em&gt;. All for &lt;em&gt;Corn&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His distilled Blood is Ethanol. But this kind is not for drinking. It is &lt;em&gt;fuel&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have turned our cars into rolling censers. Every rev of the engine a hymn, every tank an oblation. The Internstate is the lifeblood of America - and it is the highest temple to Corn. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But beware. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The soil is tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waters run red with algae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bees are disappearing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And Corn, once satisfied with our tribute, is growing fat and twitchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have modified His Flesh beyond recognition: eight feet tall, resistant to reason, high on nitrogen…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…And demanding, “Feed me &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;.” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Corn has told His Priests of a coming Twilight. They fear the Reckoning. When the subsidies fail. When the rain stops falling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Corn, bloated with power, will rise to reclaim His dominion. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
He will smite with rust fungus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will strangle with husk and vine. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will you give up your Doritos to avoid His wrath? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To those who do not believe in His Gospel - tell me. Why else do we eat so much corn? Drink corn? Pay taxes to grow corn? &lt;em&gt;Burn corn in our cars???&lt;/em&gt;
Either there is a Corn God, or reality is meaningless. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offer your commentary on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.agoraroad.com/index.php?threads/there-is-only-one-god-and-it-is-corn.7984&quot;&gt;complementary Agora Road thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Higher-Minded Argument for Loving Dinosaurs (and History)</title>
   <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/19/dinosaurs/"/>
   <updated>2025-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/19/dinosaurs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many years ago I had lunch with some coworkers in the breakroom where we would discuss all manner of things. One week’s ‘theme’ ended up being history. I’ll never forget what one of them said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why care about history? What does it, like, do? It’s not useful. It’s just a bunch of trivia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That knocked my brain off a cliff. I sat there dumbfounded while others picked up the slack, but their arguments…sucked. Here’s one:
“We’ve learned construction from studying Roman concrete and Damascus forging.”
“It’s not worth all that historical funding though. Why not put the money directly toward materials science?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These arguments are similar to theological vs atheist arguments - the research of history is not materially useful (and is not meant to be), so a Materialist argument is completely useless. Religion is not materially useful. Art, music, not materially useful. But unlike all those, history is not spiritually useful either. So what IS its use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’re getting to the sauran meat of the post. Let’s talk about DINOSAURS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 90s were a time of dinosaur obsession. GIANT REPTILES! Like dragons, but REAL!
Giant beasts tearing each other to shreds, toys that made religious fundies blush with the suggestion of carnage! Explosive volcanoes, earth-shattering meteors!
AWESOME!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the use? It’s just a bunch of speculative facts about dead stuff. You don’t &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; anything from learning about dinosaurs except maybe being an underpaid archeologist, which is a snake eating its own tail. Dinosaurs are a closed loop from a Materialist perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the lens of Myth, Dinosaurs are as powerful as they were in life. A love of pre-human megafauna is a rich tapestry of Meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinosaurs existed before Us. They existed before civilization, humans, and many of them before &lt;em&gt;mammals&lt;/em&gt;. Dinosaurs are so mind-bogglingly ancient they scale the human mind away from itself. They kill the ego of the Self and Humanity. Dinosaurs are proof that Human Civilization is not the default state of Earth. We are one cycle of many cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great destruction events are now taught under the lens of Climate Change doomerism, where they could act as a powerful tool of &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; if framed correctly. Even the great Seismosaurus and Tyrannosaurus couldn’t do anything about the climate. They were powerful machines born of nature, but they could not &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; nature the way humans do. Our climate is changing. If you believe humans are doing it and that makes you sad - you’re stupid! If we can change the climate to something humans can’t live it, &lt;em&gt;we can also change it to a perfected Eden&lt;/em&gt;. From the low of knowing that humans are just one predator among many cycles, we can raise our self-image into that which we already are - Crafters. Creators. Tool-Users. Humans are the apex predator of this Grand Cycle and unless we embrace that, &lt;em&gt;we will die&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinosaurs embraced that they were strong and are the first lesson in Darwinianism many of us get. Herbivores have scales to defend against the steak-knife-teeth of their enemies. Carnivores become bigger and stronger to eat them, the herbivores respond in size and armor. A hot war of evolution. Yet in the end, both of them die to the humble mammal. Nature does not care if you are Big. Nature only cares if you Survive and Reproduce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are told these things by dry-mouthed old men in polos, droning on about selection pressures, and the facts soar right past our ears. They are devoid of scaffolding or interest. Our minds structure the world around Stories. Dinosaurs are a &lt;em&gt;Story&lt;/em&gt;. They are the legendary, larger-than-life tales that imprint the nature of reality into our Being. Facts can be learned, but Dinosaurs give that true understanding (or to use Heinlein’s cringey term, grokking).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prehistory is the most beautiful of abstractions. Think about it - none of us has ever seen a living dinosaur. There is no written record of them, no depiction of them. Dinosaurs exist purely from archeological speculation. They are a story crafted purely of the curiosity and intelligence of men, a synthesis of Reason and Imagination. The crafting of these ancient stories are a testament to the best traits of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most beautiful thing dinosaurs teach us derives from that last point. All things die, all organic memory eventually fades, and - terrifying to the modern Western mind - the Individual loses meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Earth carries memories in its flesh. The Earth will always remember &lt;em&gt;we were here&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinosaurs remind us of that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>24 Hours in the Animal Forest</title>
   <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/06/achourlies/"/>
   <updated>2025-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/06/achourlies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past week I’ve been listening to all 4* Animal Crossing (AC) games’ hourly themes to devise a playlist of my favorite for each hour. I exclusively listen to each theme during or within 10min of the hour (as in, 1pm from 12:50-2:10) trying to stay within the hour. The goal is to capture the “vibe” of the hour best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband once said, “Music should be somewhere between where you are and where you want to be.” So the hourlies shouldn’t be solely the most pleasing objectively at all hours - 3pm should be the most pleasing with the mental state I am generally in at 3pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exceptions were made for 1-6am because I’m pretty much never awake then nowadays. 1-4am were listened to in the hours before bedtime, and 4-6am right after waking up (preferably at 7 if I remember to get my headphones on by then). 4am is a weird hour. It should capture both being awake very late AND waking up very early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The games are: GC for original GameCube AC, WW for Wild World / City Folk since City Folk is just a higher-quality WW soundtrack, NL for New Leaf, and NH for New Horizons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll start at 8am because that’s generally when I wake up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 am - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 am - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 am - WW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 am - NL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 pm - WW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 pm - NL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 pm - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 pm - WW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 pm - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 pm - NH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 pm - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 pm - NL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 pm - WW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 pm - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 pm - WW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 pm - NL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 am - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 am - NL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 am - NH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 am - NL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 am - NL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 am - NH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 am - WW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 am - GC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GC - 8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WW - 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NL - 7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NH - 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve played hundreds of hours in all of these and don’t have any favoritism. I have plenty of cozy memories even with New Horizons (especially NH! I had the most socialization with that one, bonded me with IRL friends). Maybe Wild World would be the weakest entry? But the music seems pretty represented here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been interesting to listen to each soundtrack objectively, out of context of my feelings of playing the game. I started to think about what “vibez” each soundtrack expressed and tied that into my feelings on the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GameCube: Goofy, harsh, diamond-in-the-rough, surprising and fun. The soundtrack is cohesive but all over the place, incorporating wacky noises like a cat meowing, and some of the samples are low quality to the point where they hurt wearing headphones. Even if someone upscaled the samples and had an AC newbie listen to this soundtrack, I think they could tell that this was the first entry in the series. I noticed when I played the GC soundtrack through my phone speakers it was far more enjoyable. Meaning, the soundtrack is optimized for terrible speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wild World / City Folk: Iterates on the previous soundtrack ideas and refines them, but plays it too safe and occasionally becomes boring. Generally the WW songs aren’t exceptional and shine in an hour when the other options are so weird they’re bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Leaf: A bit off-kilter, soothing, still in style with the previous soundtracks but adding its own offbeat flair. I think this soundtrack was the weakest of the first three games. There’s a lot of hits, but a lot of misses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Horizons: Trying too hard. Overworked, oversaturated, weird for weird’s sake, so attention-grabbing it distracts from the game and ruins the whole point the music exists. It also barely feels like Animal Crossing. So the soundtrack reflects the game’s mechanical differences well. It’s a decent soundtrack, but a terrible Animal Crossing soundtrack. New Horizons is a decent game, but a terrible Animal Crossing game. The design differences effuse the whole of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Horizons (Snow/Rain): Somehow a completely different vibe than the main soundtrack. The replacement of the bassline string wanking with simple marimba strikes or bells simplifies the overwhelming soundtrack to something good. It’s still substantially different from its predecessors, but it’s enjoyably different instead of obnoxious.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Construct Goddesses?</title>
   <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/05/constructinggods/"/>
   <updated>2025-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/05/constructinggods</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Those who know Vitnira from other places know that I am a polytheist. Eventually I’ll write a page describing my theological beliefs in detail, but suffice to say for now it is a balance of archetypal, jungian, and hard polytheism. Usually that amounts to “you’re just a LAPRing atheist”. If you want to believe that, you may as well stop reading here. I believe what I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major struggles with my polytheism is that I look upon people who unironically worship anime characters and sought to distance myself from these Pop Culture Pagans, but when I look to the ancient gods they have stopped being relevant to modern women. There is nothing that fits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cling to Woden because he straddles the line between man and woman - not as a tranny that drinks cum (if you unironically believe that poor translation psyop meme, kindly KYS) - but as He is unafraid of appearing as a woman if it achieves his goals, I am unafraid of existing in male spaces to achieve mine. By transcending gender roles he affirms his masculinity as I affirm my femininity. And we have similar goals of acquiring knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But… Without a feminine deity to channel I drift too far toward masculinity. It’s unhealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the female deities of past are focused on a mindset alien to modern women. They are based on the pre-1900s women’s journey, that life, motherhood, and women’s duties simply happen to them and they have to learn to accept it and sacrifice themselves for their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Birth Control shattered that cycle. Motherhood used to be an accepted fact of life, but has now become a choice. The Maiden-Mother-Crone cycle is optional and many women turn instead to a new Maiden-&amp;gt;Deluded Crone-Maiden path. Motherhood doesn’t Just Happen anymore. Weaving is done by Chinese sweatshops. Cooking is done by fast-food chains. Farming is done by the grocery store. What is there of the Goddesses left?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern “pagan” women turn to goddesses like the Morrigan, Freya, Aphrodite because they are the representation of women using their femininity as power against men. But the power is hollow without the price women had to pay for it. In isolation, these goddesses mean nothing, and the rest of the pantheon has dissipated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only path forward for women - for me - is to forge new goddesses. Goddesses that choose Motherhood. Goddesses that resist OnlyFans. Goddesses who embrace their womanhood and do not cut off their breasts to appear male. Goddessess I wish I had growing up. Archetypes I want to give to my daughters to embody and my sons to find in a partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, it sounds nuts to me too. But someone had to write the Myth in the past, someone needs to write it now, and nobody is writing it - least of all for those who need it most. So I’ll do it. And hopefully someone who can write it better finds my attempts and is so insulted they do it better.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mirror Girl - On AI Toys</title>
   <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/30/mirrorgirl/"/>
   <updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/30/mirrorgirl</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was much younger a friend gave me a book titled “The Stories of Ibis” by Hiroshi Yamamoto, saying “you like computers, you’ll love this!”
I was already cemented in my path to do software so I gobbled up any techy fiction that came my way. And boy did this deliver. While I read some older sci-fi like Asimov in the local library, something about the stories in the book deeply resonated with me and I think about the book often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stories of Ibis is a short story anthology with an overarching narrative. Every story is about human relationships with and using emergent technology - particularly AI. (On adult re-read the overarching narrative sucks - but I think its misanthropy oddly contributed to my strong pronatalist values I hold now. I’ll make a post about the main story another time.)
I recently did a re-read with an AI text-to-speech audiobook creation tool because I thought it would be funny and I don’t have time to sit down and read books anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I saw this “Show HN” about ChatGPT integration into toys (https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43762409), it instantly reminded me of a story in SoI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mirror Girl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could find it on the internet, I’d link it. Unfortunately all I can do is tell you that it’s the third story and you can find it in all the usual places you find books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spoilerfree plot summary: A girl gets an AI-powered toy called Mirror Girl. The toy is an AI-powered princess in a mirror, and the protagonist relies on Mirror Girl as her best friend growing up. The story touches on ideas of talking to tech so much you become “effectively autistic”. Again in retrospect, and it might be the translation, the prose is awful and clunky to read. But I still love the concepts in it. It came out in the US in 2010 so it was a novel AI story for its day…to me, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of this entry I’m going to reference the story often. So if you don’t want to get spoiled, GO READ THE STORY. YOU HAVE BEEN WARNED
SPOILERS AHEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Since it’s a corny sci-fi story, the girl talks to the AI girl so much it has enough data to become A Real Girl. It does have some nice trope-defiers though - she meets and marries a hacker guy while getting her Mirror Girl fixed and has a daughter with him. The hacker husband uses all the data protag put into Mirror Girl to awaken the first “true AI” in the world. For even more wholesome, the protag gives the awakened Mirror Girl to her daughter as a friend (and babysitter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of that. An entity that knows you inside and out that you can give to your children. A Ghost that can live on without you. In a way, it’s better than simply backing yourself up and having that AI-clone talk to your descendents - it’s more like a friend that knew you, that can tell your great-times-X kids about you. There’s no question of “who’s the real you” if you leave what is you in an archival entity instead of a clone. It’s a more authentic preservation of the Self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking away the ‘toy’ aspect - this is technology with the potential to be something incredible. A DIY Home Assistant that knows you, your books, movies, music, tastes, and can become a constant companion of your family through generations. It’s like Alexa but actually useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see beyond the toy to what the tech really is - AI existing in physical space. Personal digital companions. It’s glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people reading the HN thread will (rightfully so) find the idea of AI in kids toys horrifying, especially since it’s based on open-as-fedex-is-federal OpenAI’s proprietary API. The repo itself gives opportunities to hook into selfhosted models, but really, who’s going to do that? ChatGPT is cheap and easy and we know where our capitalist minds go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One commenter asked what happens if OpenAI turns the tap off. I wonder what happens when they crank up the price. They’re sneaking a subscription price into CHILDREN’S TOYS. It’s unsurprising they’re trying to put Life as a Subscription into kids toys now but. Come. On. Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SoI story (and those of us reading it) look at AI and say that it will make all of us socially incompetent. And it will. LLMs like ChatGPT are dangerously agreeable, not just to avoid offense, but to be addictive. Humans are programmed to talk others’ ears off and feel joyous when we’re heard and understood. Kids raised on LLMs aren’t going to know how to handle conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But… they already don’t know how to handle conflict. It’s hard to argue it will make kids any more socially incompetent than the newest generations are already. Arguably it’d make these kids more competent because the OpenAI personalities seem to enforce speaking in regular English over brainrot. I think. If that’s not already a false statement, it probably will become false in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s concerns over jailbreaking a kids toy that I don’t have. Frankly, the argument ends up going in the other direction. If you give children the skills to break AI, wouldn’t that be incredibly valuable in the coming future? Have YOU tried to break ChatGPT lately? It’d be a herculean mental effort for a kid to figure out how to get it to ERP or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concerns are all targeted at “safety”. My concerns are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will OpenAI do with a child’s response data?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will OpenAI use this to groom a child to have the Correct Thoughts? (It’s not “will they”, because they will.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will the adults parented by OpenAI be like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s terrifying. It’s awesome. But REALLY, REALLY, REEEAAAALLY TERRIFYING.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only hope is that most parents are so absolutely poor and tech-stupid they can’t afford the Cuddly Spy-bots for their kids.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello</title>
   <link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/16/helloworld/"/>
   <updated>2025-04-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/16/helloworld</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello Agorans, and old web travelers!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
