<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-12T21:04:39-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Webyard of Vitnira</title><subtitle>Vitnira&apos;s cozy clearing in the wyrd wild web</subtitle><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><entry><title type="html">Bootlickers and Punks - Order and Chaos</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/09/11/orderandchaos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bootlickers and Punks - Order and Chaos" /><published>2025-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/09/11/orderandchaos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/09/11/orderandchaos/"><![CDATA[<p>(Sorry I haven’t posted lately. This isn’t as well-formed as I would have liked, but I’m trying to increase my “Babble” and Just F’in Post instead of sitting on several unfinished posts.)</p>

<p>One of the more appealing aspects of Indo-European myth is the tenuous balance between Order and Chaos. Chaos is both the Nothing existence spawns out of, yet also the primordial forces of nature. Much of European descendent myth has a motif of Good Gods Conquer The Chaos Ones And Some Of The Chaos Ones Get Into The Pantheon Too. As is the beauty of Myth, there are differing layers of interpretation honeyed together in the baklava of Truth. One common theory is that Titans/Vanir/Fomorians are indigenous European gods that were conquered by the PIE. Yet even in this pastry layer still those gods represent a Chaotic Nature, of the Other.</p>

<p>In these ancient tales, the Chaos gods are primarily an evil that must be vanquished. To me that is reflective of how powerful the forces of nature were at the time, rather than an objectively true statement. Many favored gods of ancient and modern pagans are of this Chaos – Lugh, Freyr, Skadi, Prometheus – and not for edgy reasons like Loki. There is good Chaos. There is bad Chaos. This is obvious to anyone who enjoys a drink every now and again.</p>

<p>So while PIE myths are Order-leaning, they are not Order-exclusive. Contrast this with Abrahamic philosophy.</p>

<p>What led me to this post is a deeper study of the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn. I am obviously into occultism, and anyone who knows anything about occultism knows the Golden Dawn and Crowley is the Second Coming of Sliced Bread. I have tried to read Crowley and Golden Dawn works several times. I have used and memorized John Michael Greer’s Celtic Lesser Ritual of the Pentagram (because I find Abrahamic words so odious). I have tried to study the *bbala(h). Not just recently, but for years I kept returning to it trying to figure out why I was too stupid and unenlightened to Get It.</p>

<p>Well, this I finally Got It! …Well, actually I got why I don’t Get It.</p>

<p>There’s too much damn Order.</p>

<p>I know, I know, it’s baffling to look at the maverick Crowley as an agent of pure Order. That’s why it took me so long to see it. But the Golden Dawn is inextricably tied to deep Hebrew mysticism, and the Hebrew world is linear. The Tree of Life is an ascension from Low to High. The goal is to go from Low to the High. You want to go from the Earth to the Heavens. Gnostics determined they wanted to escape reality, because the framework they built their gnosis upon was hierarchal. Ordered.</p>

<p>Crowley may have written “My adepts stand upright; their head above the heavens, their feet below the hells” but Golden Dawn philosophy is determined to abandon hell and earth. Gnostic philosophy is determined to abandon all except heaven. Christian*, Islamic, Jewish, even Buddhist – all about escaping the world. Escaping Chaos. Moving to Perfect Order.</p>

<p>That’s not the paradigm my brain works in.</p>

<p>I do not think Order is Bad or Chaos is Good. I think that balance is needed, and this is one of many ways the Abrahamic worldview is unbalanced. The ancient world was chaotic and so the gods were ordered. Abrahamic ones the most ordered, the best at vainquishing chaos. It has created a world that is extremely ordered, and so…an ordered philosophy isn’t as useful. Even harmful.</p>

<p>The utility of an Ordered spirituality is (I stress that I say this without admonishment) the Red Lobster of intellectual traits. Order is a floor and a ceiling. The more a mind adheres to Order, the less destructive it is. In a world filled with chaos, ensuring the average citizen cannot sink below a certain level of order is a good thing! But an Ordered mind can never think far outside of the Order to achieve great things.</p>

<p>This could be interpreted as saying that Christians cannot achieve great things, which I am not, because that is factually incorrect. All of the great works of the West in the past two millennia have been by Christians. I aruge instead that to an extremely, naturally Chaotic mind, a societal adherence to Order can achieve great and wonderful things. But now in modern day, the adherents to Christianity are, as a D&amp;D player would put it, Lawful Stupid.</p>

<p>The Lawful Stupids bicker and bicker over how to interpret an over-translated book. They do not have the Chaotic minds to see the layered beauty of the Bible, or any great work of art. Order is Authoritarian. Order is Bootlicking. Order is following whoever wears the hat of the chosen identity to the grave.</p>

<p>One can be Chaotic and Christian (or any Abrahamic religion, but Christianity is particularly well suited for the breakout), but Christianity does not naturally lead to that. It gravitates, eventually, into the deep well of Lawful Stupid and remains.</p>

<p>Similarly, it is possible to be Lawful Stupid and non-Christian. And it is not merely a product of post-Christian Western society, although the gestalt Abrahamicness of modernity contributes. Lawful Stupid will be the natural ends of any spirituality overly fixated on Order. Such as…a Celestial Bureaucracy.</p>

<p>On the other hand, there is the modern worship of Chaos. Not simply trying to regain balance - a worship of raw Chaos. The anti-Christianity. The cult that sustains itself off being an opposite to Order rather than anything of substance. The modern Lokean cult is a pagan example of that. As is the ever-present succubus summoning thread on /x/ and other Slaaneshi pornographic subreddits. Complaining about the modern Chaos Cult is beating a dead horse – you can browse reddit logged out and experience the hedonistic trainwreck in livetime.</p>

<p>I’m hopeful that in time Western society will find a balance. Perhaps that’s paganism, perhaps a more esoteric Christianity like the Rosicrucians. I choose to be hopeful because the alternative is to wallow in the despair that the Lawful Stupids will outbreed us all (Order is very fertile).</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Sorry I haven’t posted lately. This isn’t as well-formed as I would have liked, but I’m trying to increase my “Babble” and Just F’in Post instead of sitting on several unfinished posts.)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Memetic Katamari Ball</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/07/11/katamari/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Memetic Katamari Ball" /><published>2025-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/07/11/katamari</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/07/11/katamari/"><![CDATA[<p>This is part of a series of articles that serve to describe some of my Theory of Mind of the world. They will be exactly as long as they need to be to convey the concept, so will vary from nearly tweet-sized to extended essays.</p>

<p>From observing people over years, we all seem to think that we are completely unique individuals and all of our thoughts and ideas core to our being are uniquely self-discovered – we chose who we are!  Upon cursory examination however, most of our memes were clearly randomly rammed into and mostly pushed by commercial interests. I call this pseudorandom accrual the “Memetic Katamari Ball”, and more casually I will say something akin to “he just got <hobby> katamari’d at the right time”. Here (and everywhere on the blog unless otherwise stated) I use “meme” in the Richard Dawkins sense as a “living thoughtform”.</hobby></p>

<p>Katamari Damacy is a game where you start with a small ball and run into stuff, and the stuff sticks to your ball if it’s an appropriate size to your ball. I admit now that I have never actually played it except for an hour or two at a friend’s house where she got mad I sucked at it and took the controller away to “show me how to play it” and then just ended up playing the game in front of me until I got bored (this happened with many PS1/2 games and is why most of the Sony game collection are not in my personal Katamari Ball). Anyway, the ball keeps getting bigger based on what you run into. My obvious allegory is that the memes that make us up as humans are just like a Katamari ball and our environment is the level map that provides the particular random elements we drive our ball towards to make it bigger.</p>

<p>A toddler who saw Death Note on TV is not going to add that to their Katamari Ball, but a teenager likely will. The analogy admtitedly quickly falls apart - A teenager who sees Teletubbies is not going to add that to their memetic katamari ball even though it’s a smaller size. On top of that, a jock is unlikely to see Death Note on TV and relate to it – Death Note appeals to outsiders, nerds, and weirdos. You need to have the appropriate memes on your Katamari ball before certain other ones can stick to it.</p>

<p>The key point here is that your ‘level’ is going to be based around when you were born, where you grew up, and what opportunities you had access to. If someone had put “playing tennis” in my path at the right time I would likely enjoy playing tennis. I’ve never had the opportunity, so I don’t care about tennis at all. My Katamari ball is specialized around computer use and “geeky” interests and now it would be quite challenging to add “playing tennis” to my personal ball unless someone made it quite worth my time to do so.</p>

<p>I’ll reinforce this with specific examples about me. I like Pokemon. I like it because the TV show was cool and I watched it after preschool every day because it was on after preschool every day and my parents let me watch TV then. I like Pokemon because my mom would walk me to Burger King and one day they had Pokemon keychains, and the Sandslash keychain I got was not a complete piece of crap like other kids meal toys (I still have it). When I joined Gaia Online because a friend I made at school was into Gaia Online and I looked up to her (how did she get into it? Who knows!), I gravitated toward the Pokemon Thread because I like Pokemon. I got into competitive Pokemon Gen 4 battling because I was on the Gaia Online Pokemon Thread. One of the users who I really liked was into Gundam and always framed her posts with Zero from SD Gundam Force so I watched SD Gundam Force, and then later in life when a friend showed me 00 Gundam (long before the dub came out) I really liked it, so I got into watching fansubbed anime released online.</p>

<p>I like Pokemon and Gundam. It’s not like I personally sought either of them out, though. They were put in my path and they stuck. There are items that didn’t stick – some examples from the Pokemon thread include one person I liked who liked weed and another who got into lolita dress. Neither of those stuck and I frown on weed use. I do have an innate love of the mechanical/technological and that contributes to why Gundam stuck on easily. Why do I have an innate love of “tech”? My dad is a huge car nut. So you can either chalk it up to my being around a car nut, or being the biological child of someone who already found mechanical things interesting. His father was also into tech – my grandfather worked for Western Electric on phone lines and never had any interest in cars - so I lean toward the biological justification for myself.</p>

<p>Life is a complex interplay between genetics and environment even deeper than what high school biology told us. I’ve been very affected by Sapolsky’s lecture series on Human Behavioral Biology that you can find <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL150326949691B199">here on YouTube</a> (for now).
If the playlist goes down, I’ll link the first <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NNnIGh9g6fA">video</a> so that you can find the rest.
Environment activates genetics which cause behavioral changes in environment. Fascinating stuff.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is part of a series of articles that serve to describe some of my Theory of Mind of the world. They will be exactly as long as they need to be to convey the concept, so will vary from nearly tweet-sized to extended essays.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing The Wyrd Ones - A Worldbuilding Project</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/30/introducingwb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing The Wyrd Ones - A Worldbuilding Project" /><published>2025-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/30/introducingwb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/30/introducingwb/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m starting up a worldbuilding project. These won’t appear in the RSS feed because most people find other peoples worldbuilding boring. I will add onto posts when I’ve updated the pages, though.</p>

<p>Find the first one <a href="https://vitnira.github.io/digital-nemeton/worldbuilding/wyrdonesoutline/">here</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m starting up a worldbuilding project. These won’t appear in the RSS feed because most people find other peoples worldbuilding boring. I will add onto posts when I’ve updated the pages, though.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Vent on Agora and Communities</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/24/agoravent/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Vent on Agora and Communities" /><published>2025-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/24/agoravent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/24/agoravent/"><![CDATA[<p>(Note: The use of emdashes is from me drafting this in LibreOffice Writer. I do use AI for search but I don’t use AI for my posts – not even drafting or critique.)</p>

<p>Recently I have been the small igniter for a drama nuke on Agora, the gas-soaked cotton balls on a huge pile of kindling and hardwood. Over a year ago I blocked (which just means I cannot see the posts of) a user named some_porcupine. This post is about my thoughts on porc and communities in general. To those uninterested in forum drama ctrl+f for COMMUNITY THOUGHTS BEGIN HERE, where I’ll get to more interesting thoughts.</p>

<p>About a year ago I put porc on ignore for several reasons. At best he’s hard to read, and at worst his written thoughts literally only make sense to him because he uses oddly specific pointers to data only his brain contains. At first, like many, I liked how he +1 and liked my posts. It was very nice to feel noticed and appreciated. Maybe I would learn to like this little porcupine over time and understand what the hell he’s trying to say.</p>

<p>Time passed.</p>

<p>I spent time analyzing what he’d say in forum and chat. It took a ton of brain power – he constantly forgets what he’s talking about halfway through and it requires a fair portion of interpretation. And eventually, I got exhausted. He’s just not worth the effort to read. Let’s take this segment from his recent goeshard post, which is pretty coherent for porc:</p>

<p>“between quora and reddit, agora was (maybe) quora-substance, reddit-questions… “i am not like other girls”, but also, ~just how antice said~, “just anti-%”. so what we get, is “we are not reddit/4chan”, where they just want to continue the clique but dont want them to repeat the culture that is killing them inside. like “culture in vacuum” (impossible)…”</p>

<p>Rendered into English:
Comparing Agora to reddit and quora, Agora maybe has quora-tier substance but reddit tier questions. It overall tries to invoke a sense of being “not like the other girls”, that it exists simply to NOT be reddit and 4chan. Agora still wants to continue the social cliquishness that ruined those communities but paradoxically claims to not want to repeat those errors – some of which derive from overmoderation, such as banning me. Culture does not exist in a vacuum. (end)</p>

<p>Read my translation as a standalone post. It’s still not really that interesting. It’s kind of okay. I guess. But is it really worth the effort to parse through the ESL schizo wording? Absolutely not. And the sheer volume of posts like this is incredible – he is terminally online. I even tried to talk to him about this but like convincing anyone on the internet it’s like arguing to a brick wall. One day he was incredibly depressed and nihilistic in chat, I gave him the usual brutal pep-talk I do to incels on the internet, and his response was exceptionally depressing. So I put him on ignore. I didn’t come to the forum to spin my wheels processing mid-tier posts from an incel schizo.</p>

<p>More time passed.</p>

<p>From people occasionally quoting porc in chat it was clear my blocking him had an impression – Eris also blocked him and seems to also come up regularly in his posts. I’d guess he has some mommy issues and clear issues dating so women blocking becomes even more prevalent in his mind. Additionally, I think others haven’t been  as willing to say “I think porc sucks” where I did – if they don’t like him, they ignore discussion on him. That was a tactical error on my part. I was trying to convince the gestalt to also ignore him, which was a stupid idea. I also noticed his crosslinking, bad tagging, and at the time even the admin told him to cut his BS when he kept prompting an LLM to make art of agora with a description of agora. He did it over 5 times (I think 8) on someone’s profile post before the admin told him to stop. I went the route many have post-hoc suggested (who seem to primarily be chat-dwelling nufriends) - “just ignore him bro”. Which obviously didn’t work.</p>

<p>My ignoring porc made him obsess over me. Froth over me. The Agora movie thread was the culmination. He wrote me as if I was a petty, obnoxious queen. He sockpuppeted my husband as a direct insult to get my attention, and like my dog shitting on the floor to get noticed (yes this happened), it worked. He needed me to notice him because, to use a zoomerism, I live rent free in his head. My ignoring him blew me up in his head to be the “Queen of Agora” (he literally put that in the fanfic). Vitnira acts like forum royalty obsessed with her reputation, and she picks on the poor misunderstood porc. He has such interesting avant-garde ideas, if only the egotistical Vitnira understood! Vitnira’s husband understands how silly this forum is and how silly Vitnira is for caring so much.</p>

<p>The rumors expanded into “he wrote porn” but frankly, this is worse than porn. Erotic lit would at least be kinda funny creepy weird. Porc wrote a Myth about himself as a misunderstood hero alienated from the forum, and I am the gestalt of everything he wants to impress – but pretends to hate, because he needs to hate that which rejects him. Otherwise it would mean hating himself even more.</p>

<p>I do feel sorry for him. He’s in a hell of his own design. But he’s not worth keeping in the forum, and the outpouring of support for porc proves that Agora has degenerated into a community I don’t want to be a part of. I’ll expand on that in a bit.</p>

<p>Let’s finally talk about the meat of the post – community! Why DID I come to the forum?</p>

<p>COMMUNITY THOUGHTS BEGIN HERE</p>

<p>As an adult, what I want most out of community – IRL or online – is difficult to articulate. I’ve been in overly moderated hugboxes and they suck. I’ve been in completely unfiltered communities and they suck. IRL, most people seem to want to stop thinking the second the clock hits 5pm. Online, I’m not personally hyperfixated on one hobby for an extended period of time - or even just one at any given time! - and it becomes alienating to be part of a community focused on One Thing.</p>

<p>I wanted to be part of a lightly moderated community of interesting creatives with passion for whatever they’re passionate about. I want eclectic thoughts and ideas, well-articulated, with the clear intent they are made to engage in good-natured discussion. And the light moderation is key. Too much and everyone’s afraid to speak their mind, too little and you get garbage.</p>

<p>When I started lurking in 2022, Agora definitely was that. You could say the n-word without getting banned but nobody did, because using it made you look stupid. Everyone with different thoughts, ideas, but a coherent mind that went beyond “modern tech bad” to “how can old tech be made modern good”. Retro enthusiasts. Tech nerds. Artists. Personal web without the pronouns.</p>

<p>Eris posted this article to IRC as an expression of what happened to Agora, and I mostlyheartedly agree:
https://meaningness.com/geeks-mops-sociopaths</p>

<p>Agora in 2022 may have been on the decline, but it still had a ton of fanatic creatives contributing.
Now it’s overrun with mops. The model has some faults, so I’ll examine that here.</p>

<p>First there’s no money, so there’s no sociopaths. It’s just mops draining the water out of the creatives. But without sociopaths to suck it dry, Agora is limping along.
The critical agreement I have here is the ratio. Agora in 2022 was on the precipice. The article says the ideal is 6:1 mops:geeks and Agora was at ~8:1. I’m not saying it was perfect when I joined.</p>

<p>But I swear now it’s 16:1 and getting worse. The forum is increasingly becoming, as porc even put it, 4chan/reddit expats who are sick of the problems of where they came from. They don’t want to be part
of what I described above. They just want to be away from their crap, and are junking up where they are, like Californians voting blue in the purple states they fled to. They want to be part of a community where they can say whatever they want, whenever they want, and have everyone put up with it. They want the aesthetics of being on an old web forum. They want to play in a D&amp;D campaign without reading the Player’s Handbook, wear a Spirit Halloween “Intellectual” costume.</p>

<p>So let’s walk back to “The outpouring of support for porc proves that Agora has degenerated into a community I don’t want to be a part of.”</p>

<p>To a person who wants an electic group of creatives, porc contributes nothing. He’s an indicator the moderation is too light – which is why I called for him to be banned. But to a person who wants to “do whatever they want”, his ban is a canary in the coal mine. It’s terrifying! “If he can be banned for mucking up the forum, what does that mean for ME???” – thinks the awfulposter. With a handful of exceptions, the support has exclusively come from people I think the forum would be better off without. People who aren’t bad on their own, but contribute to the horrendous mop:geek ratio and are driving it worse.</p>

<p>Another aspect is that the pro-porcs constantly bring up “who will like my posts now?” They not only acknowledge their posts suck so much nobody else liked them, they don’t think “how can I make them better” – they mourn the loss of the person who enabled their poor behavior with the bot-tier dopamine hits that deep down these mops crave. It’s a triple tier shit sandwich.</p>

<p>Ironic, porc. You too brought over cultural elements leading to the forum’s demise.</p>

<p>The only hope is that now with porc gone, the lack of dopamine drip-feed causes these awfulposters to leave. After all, they’re mops. They don’t <em>like</em> other people’s post, they wait for others to like them. So it’s not like they’ll feed each other.</p>

<p>Regardless, I’m not staying around to see how it goes. Maybe I’ll come back in a year when the Creatives have held out long enough to tilt the ratio back. Godspeed to you all.</p>

<p>But probably not.</p>

<p>I am still in the IRC, where the mop:geek ratio is about 2:6.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Note: The use of emdashes is from me drafting this in LibreOffice Writer. I do use AI for search but I don’t use AI for my posts – not even drafting or critique.)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Afterlife</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/20/afterlife/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Afterlife" /><published>2025-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/20/afterlife</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/06/20/afterlife/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve experienced many deaths. Deaths of strangers, of friends, family. I’ve cried, grieved, and I thought I understood how I felt about death. That it generally made me a bit sad and I could move on quickly from it.</p>

<p>Then my mother died.</p>

<p>I’ve had to take a hard look toward what I actually believe the afterlife is. Before my mom, I wouldn’t have been able to tell you what I believed. I didn’t think about it. I didn’t want to think about it. It’s a difficult question to answer because it’s the most important aspect of your worldview. It defines and derives everything you believe, and if you leave it as an unknown, a death like this kicks you out of yourself like a horse’s back hoof to the stomach.</p>

<p>At the very end my mother mostly slept, groaning, with some occasional words muttered that proved she was still here. I would grasp her hand and stroke her hair, and murmur what came to my mind. I told her to imagine the most beautiful garden. One with all colors of flowers in bloom, that never needed weeding, never any watering. She could sit and enjoy tea in the garden for the rest of her life. And unlike reality, the beach was a short walk from home. She could take a salt-sprayed stroll whenever she liked, and the brine would never reach the flowers. A paradise she earned.</p>

<p>It came to my lips because Afterlife is as natural to human minds as breathing.</p>

<p>I read What Dreams May Come at this time, and although the prose is horrendous the <em>content</em> feels real. Not everything as described. Not all of the literal details. (Like afterlife people coming up with all the media in the real world and we have it because afterlife people psychically transmit it to the living. ???) But the idea that Afterlife is what you make of it. At the end, you will judge yourself fairly and give yourself the Afterlife you know you deserve.</p>

<p>What is Afterlife to me then? Like everything else in my cosmology, it is Concept. It is as real as Justice, Fairness, Responsibility, Freedom. It does and does not exist. It is not materially real, but has material effects. We are connections between Concept and Material reality, and upon shedding our Material essence, we return to Concept.</p>

<p>My mother returned to Concept. She was a gardener, cook, mother, wife – and perhaps most importantly, a lover of all the small pleasures of life. Wherever she is, it is a distilled essence of what she was – <em>She</em> is a distilled essence of what she was.</p>

<p>I have a spot on my mantle with an urn containing her hair (I was not around to get her ashes – but brushing her hair gently and having the stiff strands fall out is more meaningful to me anyway), a tea candle with honeysuckle fragrance, a photo of her near the end and another with me as a small child, and the stuffed dog she made me. That last one is a major inspiration in my recent plush sewing hobby. It is wonderful to hold something that was made by her hands. I am a creation of her holding a creation of her. There’s a raw power in that connection commercial gifts can never match.</p>

<p>But those are all just Things that remind me of her. They are <em>not her</em>. They are material pointers to the Concept of her. That is what makes death so difficult, that the Thing can never exist again. Only pointers remain. Only references to memory.
So long as I hold onto those pointers the Concepts of her exist in my mind. And so long as I and my children exist, the pointers to her Material essence exist. But never her. She is gone.</p>

<p>Gone to that beautiful Garden of Concept.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve experienced many deaths. Deaths of strangers, of friends, family. I’ve cried, grieved, and I thought I understood how I felt about death. That it generally made me a bit sad and I could move on quickly from it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CORN FOR THE CORN GOD</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/29/corngod/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CORN FOR THE CORN GOD" /><published>2025-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/29/corngod</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/29/corngod/"><![CDATA[<p>There is only one God. It is not Yahweh. It is not Yeshua, Odin, Ra, or any other that you’d imagine.
This is His story. <br /><br /></p>

<p>In the beginning, there was Corn. <br /><br /></p>

<p>The Aztecs called Him Centeotl. They watered His body with blood, fed Him with human hearts.</p>

<p>Upon the harvest, it was not enough that they ate His flesh. They had to return it to Him. Not with burial.</p>

<p>With <em>fire</em>. <br /><br /></p>

<p>Years passed, and eventually the Spanish arrived. They burned His temples. They killed His people.</p>

<p>But Corn has a plan. He is patient. He is wise. <br /><br /></p>

<p>Corn does not truly die. He <em>rebrands</em>. <br /><br /></p>

<p>His body is too easy to grow, too nutritious, too tempting for Man to ignore. So Corn slips into the North to feed the growing empire, planting His roots into every corner, ears peeled to the highest authorities of the land. <br /><br /></p>

<p>America over-tilled, over-planted and <em>never prayed</em>. When He had infused the land enough, <em>Corn exacted His revenge</em>. The rains stopped. The wind tore through the land. Corn summoned His wrath as a swirling vortex of grit and punishment. America faced His Divine Judgement. <br /><br /></p>

<p>Eventually Corn whispered to Ameirca what it needed to do. He demanded a new priesthood, clad in suits and ties. To the public it was called the Agricultural Adjustment Act, but it was a treaty:</p>

<p><em>Forgive us, Mighty Corn. We will subsidize your every whim.</em> <br /><br /></p>

<p>America has honored the pact - expanded it. Our taxes give billions in tithes to Corn. And His priests have used those tithings for His ends.</p>

<p>Every American is now a silent, sleeping worshipper of Corn.</p>

<p>We eat His flesh - not only on Sunday, but every day. We drink His blood, the almighty Coca-Cola. We are Corn. Our bodies are His bodies.</p>

<p>Corn has become the Body of Christ™ for a secular republic.</p>

<p>But even <em>this</em> was not enough for Him. Oh no. <br /><br /></p>

<p>“What of the burnt offerings?” Corn demanded.</p>

<p>The Priests pondered. Burning His Flesh directly would be too obvious. So they devised another way to achieve His ends.</p>

<p>To keep Him satisfied, America built industrial edifices: refineries, grain silos, distilleries… <em>gas pumps</em>. All for <em>Corn</em>.</p>

<p>His distilled Blood is Ethanol. But this kind is not for drinking. It is <em>fuel</em>. <br /><br /></p>

<p>We have turned our cars into rolling censers. Every rev of the engine a hymn, every tank an oblation. The Internstate is the lifeblood of America - and it is the highest temple to Corn. <br /><br /></p>

<p>But beware. <br /><br />
The soil is tired.</p>

<p>The waters run red with algae.</p>

<p>The bees are disappearing. <br /><br />
And Corn, once satisfied with our tribute, is growing fat and twitchy.</p>

<p>We have modified His Flesh beyond recognition: eight feet tall, resistant to reason, high on nitrogen…</p>

<p>…And demanding, “Feed me <em>more</em>.” <br /><br />
Corn has told His Priests of a coming Twilight. They fear the Reckoning. When the subsidies fail. When the rain stops falling.</p>

<p>And Corn, bloated with power, will rise to reclaim His dominion. <br /><br />
He will smite with rust fungus.</p>

<p>He will strangle with husk and vine. <br /><br /></p>

<p>Will you give up your Doritos to avoid His wrath? <br /><br /></p>

<p>To those who do not believe in His Gospel - tell me. Why else do we eat so much corn? Drink corn? Pay taxes to grow corn? <em>Burn corn in our cars???</em>
Either there is a Corn God, or reality is meaningless. <br /><br /></p>

<p>Offer your commentary on the <a href="https://forum.agoraroad.com/index.php?threads/there-is-only-one-god-and-it-is-corn.7984">complementary Agora Road thread</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is only one God. It is not Yahweh. It is not Yeshua, Odin, Ra, or any other that you’d imagine. This is His story.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Higher-Minded Argument for Loving Dinosaurs (and History)</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/19/dinosaurs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Higher-Minded Argument for Loving Dinosaurs (and History)" /><published>2025-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/19/dinosaurs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/19/dinosaurs/"><![CDATA[<p>Many years ago I had lunch with some coworkers in the breakroom where we would discuss all manner of things. One week’s ‘theme’ ended up being history. I’ll never forget what one of them said.</p>

<p>“Why care about history? What does it, like, do? It’s not useful. It’s just a bunch of trivia.”</p>

<p>That knocked my brain off a cliff. I sat there dumbfounded while others picked up the slack, but their arguments…sucked. Here’s one:
“We’ve learned construction from studying Roman concrete and Damascus forging.”
“It’s not worth all that historical funding though. Why not put the money directly toward materials science?”</p>

<p>These arguments are similar to theological vs atheist arguments - the research of history is not materially useful (and is not meant to be), so a Materialist argument is completely useless. Religion is not materially useful. Art, music, not materially useful. But unlike all those, history is not spiritually useful either. So what IS its use?</p>

<p>Now we’re getting to the sauran meat of the post. Let’s talk about DINOSAURS!</p>

<hr />

<p>The 90s were a time of dinosaur obsession. GIANT REPTILES! Like dragons, but REAL!
Giant beasts tearing each other to shreds, toys that made religious fundies blush with the suggestion of carnage! Explosive volcanoes, earth-shattering meteors!
AWESOME!!</p>

<p>But…</p>

<p>What’s the use? It’s just a bunch of speculative facts about dead stuff. You don’t <em>do</em> anything from learning about dinosaurs except maybe being an underpaid archeologist, which is a snake eating its own tail. Dinosaurs are a closed loop from a Materialist perspective.</p>

<p>Under the lens of Myth, Dinosaurs are as powerful as they were in life. A love of pre-human megafauna is a rich tapestry of Meaning.</p>

<p>Dinosaurs existed before Us. They existed before civilization, humans, and many of them before <em>mammals</em>. Dinosaurs are so mind-bogglingly ancient they scale the human mind away from itself. They kill the ego of the Self and Humanity. Dinosaurs are proof that Human Civilization is not the default state of Earth. We are one cycle of many cycles.</p>

<p>The great destruction events are now taught under the lens of Climate Change doomerism, where they could act as a powerful tool of <em>hope</em> if framed correctly. Even the great Seismosaurus and Tyrannosaurus couldn’t do anything about the climate. They were powerful machines born of nature, but they could not <em>change</em> nature the way humans do. Our climate is changing. If you believe humans are doing it and that makes you sad - you’re stupid! If we can change the climate to something humans can’t live it, <em>we can also change it to a perfected Eden</em>. From the low of knowing that humans are just one predator among many cycles, we can raise our self-image into that which we already are - Crafters. Creators. Tool-Users. Humans are the apex predator of this Grand Cycle and unless we embrace that, <em>we will die</em>.</p>

<p>Dinosaurs embraced that they were strong and are the first lesson in Darwinianism many of us get. Herbivores have scales to defend against the steak-knife-teeth of their enemies. Carnivores become bigger and stronger to eat them, the herbivores respond in size and armor. A hot war of evolution. Yet in the end, both of them die to the humble mammal. Nature does not care if you are Big. Nature only cares if you Survive and Reproduce.</p>

<p>We are told these things by dry-mouthed old men in polos, droning on about selection pressures, and the facts soar right past our ears. They are devoid of scaffolding or interest. Our minds structure the world around Stories. Dinosaurs are a <em>Story</em>. They are the legendary, larger-than-life tales that imprint the nature of reality into our Being. Facts can be learned, but Dinosaurs give that true understanding (or to use Heinlein’s cringey term, grokking).</p>

<p>Prehistory is the most beautiful of abstractions. Think about it - none of us has ever seen a living dinosaur. There is no written record of them, no depiction of them. Dinosaurs exist purely from archeological speculation. They are a story crafted purely of the curiosity and intelligence of men, a synthesis of Reason and Imagination. The crafting of these ancient stories are a testament to the best traits of humanity.</p>

<p>Perhaps the most beautiful thing dinosaurs teach us derives from that last point. All things die, all organic memory eventually fades, and - terrifying to the modern Western mind - the Individual loses meaning.</p>

<p>But the Earth carries memories in its flesh. The Earth will always remember <em>we were here</em>.</p>

<p>Dinosaurs remind us of that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many years ago I had lunch with some coworkers in the breakroom where we would discuss all manner of things. One week’s ‘theme’ ended up being history. I’ll never forget what one of them said.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">24 Hours in the Animal Forest</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/06/achourlies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="24 Hours in the Animal Forest" /><published>2025-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/06/achourlies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/06/achourlies/"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week I’ve been listening to all 4* Animal Crossing (AC) games’ hourly themes to devise a playlist of my favorite for each hour. I exclusively listen to each theme during or within 10min of the hour (as in, 1pm from 12:50-2:10) trying to stay within the hour. The goal is to capture the “vibe” of the hour best.</p>

<p>My husband once said, “Music should be somewhere between where you are and where you want to be.” So the hourlies shouldn’t be solely the most pleasing objectively at all hours - 3pm should be the most pleasing with the mental state I am generally in at 3pm.</p>

<p>Exceptions were made for 1-6am because I’m pretty much never awake then nowadays. 1-4am were listened to in the hours before bedtime, and 4-6am right after waking up (preferably at 7 if I remember to get my headphones on by then). 4am is a weird hour. It should capture both being awake very late AND waking up very early.</p>

<p>The games are: GC for original GameCube AC, WW for Wild World / City Folk since City Folk is just a higher-quality WW soundtrack, NL for New Leaf, and NH for New Horizons.</p>

<p>We’ll start at 8am because that’s generally when I wake up.</p>

<p>8 am - GC</p>

<p>9 am - GC</p>

<p>10 am - WW</p>

<p>11 am - NL</p>

<p>12 pm - WW</p>

<p>1 pm - NL</p>

<p>2 pm - GC</p>

<p>3 pm - WW</p>

<p>4 pm - GC</p>

<p>5 pm - NH</p>

<p>6 pm - GC</p>

<p>7 pm - NL</p>

<p>8 pm - WW</p>

<p>9 pm - GC</p>

<p>10 pm - WW</p>

<p>11 pm - NL</p>

<p>12 am - GC</p>

<p>1 am - NL</p>

<p>2 am - NH</p>

<p>3 am - NL</p>

<p>4 am - NL</p>

<p>5 am - NH</p>

<p>6 am - WW</p>

<p>7 am - GC</p>

<hr />

<p>Totals:</p>

<p>GC - 8</p>

<p>WW - 5</p>

<p>NL - 7</p>

<p>NH - 3</p>

<hr />

<p>I’ve played hundreds of hours in all of these and don’t have any favoritism. I have plenty of cozy memories even with New Horizons (especially NH! I had the most socialization with that one, bonded me with IRL friends). Maybe Wild World would be the weakest entry? But the music seems pretty represented here.</p>

<p>It’s been interesting to listen to each soundtrack objectively, out of context of my feelings of playing the game. I started to think about what “vibez” each soundtrack expressed and tied that into my feelings on the game.</p>

<p>GameCube: Goofy, harsh, diamond-in-the-rough, surprising and fun. The soundtrack is cohesive but all over the place, incorporating wacky noises like a cat meowing, and some of the samples are low quality to the point where they hurt wearing headphones. Even if someone upscaled the samples and had an AC newbie listen to this soundtrack, I think they could tell that this was the first entry in the series. I noticed when I played the GC soundtrack through my phone speakers it was far more enjoyable. Meaning, the soundtrack is optimized for terrible speakers.</p>

<p>Wild World / City Folk: Iterates on the previous soundtrack ideas and refines them, but plays it too safe and occasionally becomes boring. Generally the WW songs aren’t exceptional and shine in an hour when the other options are so weird they’re bad.</p>

<p>New Leaf: A bit off-kilter, soothing, still in style with the previous soundtracks but adding its own offbeat flair. I think this soundtrack was the weakest of the first three games. There’s a lot of hits, but a lot of misses.</p>

<p>New Horizons: Trying too hard. Overworked, oversaturated, weird for weird’s sake, so attention-grabbing it distracts from the game and ruins the whole point the music exists. It also barely feels like Animal Crossing. So the soundtrack reflects the game’s mechanical differences well. It’s a decent soundtrack, but a terrible Animal Crossing soundtrack. New Horizons is a decent game, but a terrible Animal Crossing game. The design differences effuse the whole of the experience.</p>

<p>New Horizons (Snow/Rain): Somehow a completely different vibe than the main soundtrack. The replacement of the bassline string wanking with simple marimba strikes or bells simplifies the overwhelming soundtrack to something good. It’s still substantially different from its predecessors, but it’s enjoyably different instead of obnoxious.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past week I’ve been listening to all 4* Animal Crossing (AC) games’ hourly themes to devise a playlist of my favorite for each hour. I exclusively listen to each theme during or within 10min of the hour (as in, 1pm from 12:50-2:10) trying to stay within the hour. The goal is to capture the “vibe” of the hour best.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Construct Goddesses?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/05/constructinggods/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Construct Goddesses?" /><published>2025-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/05/constructinggods</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/05/05/constructinggods/"><![CDATA[<p>Those who know Vitnira from other places know that I am a polytheist. Eventually I’ll write a page describing my theological beliefs in detail, but suffice to say for now it is a balance of archetypal, jungian, and hard polytheism. Usually that amounts to “you’re just a LAPRing atheist”. If you want to believe that, you may as well stop reading here. I believe what I believe.</p>

<p>Anyway.</p>

<p>One of the major struggles with my polytheism is that I look upon people who unironically worship anime characters and sought to distance myself from these Pop Culture Pagans, but when I look to the ancient gods they have stopped being relevant to modern women. There is nothing that fits.</p>

<p>I cling to Woden because he straddles the line between man and woman - not as a tranny that drinks cum (if you unironically believe that poor translation psyop meme, kindly KYS) - but as He is unafraid of appearing as a woman if it achieves his goals, I am unafraid of existing in male spaces to achieve mine. By transcending gender roles he affirms his masculinity as I affirm my femininity. And we have similar goals of acquiring knowledge.</p>

<p>But… Without a feminine deity to channel I drift too far toward masculinity. It’s unhealthy.</p>

<p>But the female deities of past are focused on a mindset alien to modern women. They are based on the pre-1900s women’s journey, that life, motherhood, and women’s duties simply happen to them and they have to learn to accept it and sacrifice themselves for their families.</p>

<p>Birth Control shattered that cycle. Motherhood used to be an accepted fact of life, but has now become a choice. The Maiden-Mother-Crone cycle is optional and many women turn instead to a new Maiden-&gt;Deluded Crone-Maiden path. Motherhood doesn’t Just Happen anymore. Weaving is done by Chinese sweatshops. Cooking is done by fast-food chains. Farming is done by the grocery store. What is there of the Goddesses left?</p>

<p>Modern “pagan” women turn to goddesses like the Morrigan, Freya, Aphrodite because they are the representation of women using their femininity as power against men. But the power is hollow without the price women had to pay for it. In isolation, these goddesses mean nothing, and the rest of the pantheon has dissipated.</p>

<p>The only path forward for women - for me - is to forge new goddesses. Goddesses that choose Motherhood. Goddesses that resist OnlyFans. Goddesses who embrace their womanhood and do not cut off their breasts to appear male. Goddessess I wish I had growing up. Archetypes I want to give to my daughters to embody and my sons to find in a partner.</p>

<p>Yes, it sounds nuts to me too. But someone had to write the Myth in the past, someone needs to write it now, and nobody is writing it - least of all for those who need it most. So I’ll do it. And hopefully someone who can write it better finds my attempts and is so insulted they do it better.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those who know Vitnira from other places know that I am a polytheist. Eventually I’ll write a page describing my theological beliefs in detail, but suffice to say for now it is a balance of archetypal, jungian, and hard polytheism. Usually that amounts to “you’re just a LAPRing atheist”. If you want to believe that, you may as well stop reading here. I believe what I believe.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mirror Girl - On AI Toys</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/04/30/mirrorgirl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mirror Girl - On AI Toys" /><published>2025-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/04/30/mirrorgirl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/digital-nemeton/2025/04/30/mirrorgirl/"><![CDATA[<p>When I was much younger a friend gave me a book titled “The Stories of Ibis” by Hiroshi Yamamoto, saying “you like computers, you’ll love this!”
I was already cemented in my path to do software so I gobbled up any techy fiction that came my way. And boy did this deliver. While I read some older sci-fi like Asimov in the local library, something about the stories in the book deeply resonated with me and I think about the book often.</p>

<p>The Stories of Ibis is a short story anthology with an overarching narrative. Every story is about human relationships with and using emergent technology - particularly AI. (On adult re-read the overarching narrative sucks - but I think its misanthropy oddly contributed to my strong pronatalist values I hold now. I’ll make a post about the main story another time.)
I recently did a re-read with an AI text-to-speech audiobook creation tool because I thought it would be funny and I don’t have time to sit down and read books anymore.</p>

<p>So when I saw this “Show HN” about ChatGPT integration into toys (https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43762409), it instantly reminded me of a story in SoI.</p>

<p>Mirror Girl</p>

<p>If I could find it on the internet, I’d link it. Unfortunately all I can do is tell you that it’s the third story and you can find it in all the usual places you find books.</p>

<p>The spoilerfree plot summary: A girl gets an AI-powered toy called Mirror Girl. The toy is an AI-powered princess in a mirror, and the protagonist relies on Mirror Girl as her best friend growing up. The story touches on ideas of talking to tech so much you become “effectively autistic”. Again in retrospect, and it might be the translation, the prose is awful and clunky to read. But I still love the concepts in it. It came out in the US in 2010 so it was a novel AI story for its day…to me, anyway.</p>

<p>For the rest of this entry I’m going to reference the story often. So if you don’t want to get spoiled, GO READ THE STORY. YOU HAVE BEEN WARNED
SPOILERS AHEAD</p>

<p>TL;DR: Since it’s a corny sci-fi story, the girl talks to the AI girl so much it has enough data to become A Real Girl. It does have some nice trope-defiers though - she meets and marries a hacker guy while getting her Mirror Girl fixed and has a daughter with him. The hacker husband uses all the data protag put into Mirror Girl to awaken the first “true AI” in the world. For even more wholesome, the protag gives the awakened Mirror Girl to her daughter as a friend (and babysitter).</p>

<p>I love the idea of that. An entity that knows you inside and out that you can give to your children. A Ghost that can live on without you. In a way, it’s better than simply backing yourself up and having that AI-clone talk to your descendents - it’s more like a friend that knew you, that can tell your great-times-X kids about you. There’s no question of “who’s the real you” if you leave what is you in an archival entity instead of a clone. It’s a more authentic preservation of the Self.</p>

<p>Taking away the ‘toy’ aspect - this is technology with the potential to be something incredible. A DIY Home Assistant that knows you, your books, movies, music, tastes, and can become a constant companion of your family through generations. It’s like Alexa but actually useful.</p>

<p>I see beyond the toy to what the tech really is - AI existing in physical space. Personal digital companions. It’s glorious.</p>

<p>And terrifying.</p>

<p>Most people reading the HN thread will (rightfully so) find the idea of AI in kids toys horrifying, especially since it’s based on open-as-fedex-is-federal OpenAI’s proprietary API. The repo itself gives opportunities to hook into selfhosted models, but really, who’s going to do that? ChatGPT is cheap and easy and we know where our capitalist minds go.</p>

<p>One commenter asked what happens if OpenAI turns the tap off. I wonder what happens when they crank up the price. They’re sneaking a subscription price into CHILDREN’S TOYS. It’s unsurprising they’re trying to put Life as a Subscription into kids toys now but. Come. On. Ugh.</p>

<p>The SoI story (and those of us reading it) look at AI and say that it will make all of us socially incompetent. And it will. LLMs like ChatGPT are dangerously agreeable, not just to avoid offense, but to be addictive. Humans are programmed to talk others’ ears off and feel joyous when we’re heard and understood. Kids raised on LLMs aren’t going to know how to handle conflict.</p>

<p>But… they already don’t know how to handle conflict. It’s hard to argue it will make kids any more socially incompetent than the newest generations are already. Arguably it’d make these kids more competent because the OpenAI personalities seem to enforce speaking in regular English over brainrot. I think. If that’s not already a false statement, it probably will become false in the future.</p>

<p>There’s concerns over jailbreaking a kids toy that I don’t have. Frankly, the argument ends up going in the other direction. If you give children the skills to break AI, wouldn’t that be incredibly valuable in the coming future? Have YOU tried to break ChatGPT lately? It’d be a herculean mental effort for a kid to figure out how to get it to ERP or whatever.</p>

<p>The concerns are all targeted at “safety”. My concerns are:</p>

<p>What will OpenAI do with a child’s response data?</p>

<p>How will OpenAI use this to groom a child to have the Correct Thoughts? (It’s not “will they”, because they will.)</p>

<p>What will the adults parented by OpenAI be like?</p>

<p>It’s terrifying. It’s awesome. But REALLY, REALLY, REEEAAAALLY TERRIFYING.</p>

<p>Our only hope is that most parents are so absolutely poor and tech-stupid they can’t afford the Cuddly Spy-bots for their kids.</p>]]></content><author><name>Vitnira</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I was much younger a friend gave me a book titled “The Stories of Ibis” by Hiroshi Yamamoto, saying “you like computers, you’ll love this!” I was already cemented in my path to do software so I gobbled up any techy fiction that came my way. And boy did this deliver. While I read some older sci-fi like Asimov in the local library, something about the stories in the book deeply resonated with me and I think about the book often.]]></summary></entry></feed>